(upbeat music)
We've built some report visualizations
along the way in this course,
but module seven is gonna
take us on a deeper dive
of the full capability of
Power BI's reporting feature.
You're gonna be introduced
to the fundamental concepts
and principles of designing
and building a report.
That includes selecting
the correct visuals,
designing a page layout and
applying basic but critical functionality.
The important topic of designing for
accessibility is also covered in this module.
We'll be using the retail
sample analysis desktop file
we've been working in
and the histogram Excel
file that is in the video
description below.
We have multiple lessons in this
module as you can see on the slide.
Everything from designing and
creating a report through accessibility.
Take a few moments and
review the lesson topics
and then switch to your
retail analysis sample file.
There are many methods
used to design a report.
Some people like to draw out a report
on a piece of paper and design from that.
Others like to look at previously created
reports maybe by other people that you see
and you use those as
a basis for your design.
In the retail analysis sample
file, let's go to the overview page.
So maybe you're looking at this
and someone else created this report
and you see a couple of things on
here that you would like to design.
You can use these as a starting
point for your visualization design.
Other people like to design from scratch.
There's no right or wrong answer.
You can design from whatever
perspective you want to design from.
We'll revisit these already
created report pages
later in this module
for some tips and tricks
on how to recreate some
of these visualizations.
For now, we're gonna start a new page
by clicking the plus sign to
the right of your page tabs
and we're gonna create
a pie chart visualization.
In the visualizations pane, you're gonna
locate and select the pie chart visualization
and it puts the framework of
the visualization on the canvas.
I'm gonna go ahead and resize the framework
so it's about the width of the canvas.
That's not a necessary step.
It's just something I choose to do now.
And in this pie chart, we wanna show regular
sales units and markdown sales units.
So in the fields pane to the right,
you're gonna expand the sales table
and you're gonna identify
the regular sales units field
and again, if you wanna see more of the
field name, you can expand the fields table
by going in the border between it and
visualizations and clicking and dragging.
So we're looking for the field in the sales
table that's called regular sales units
and I'm gonna just drag it into
the framework of my pie chart.
That's one way of
getting that field in there.
Now we wanna look for markdown sales
units field and this time what I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna check the box
in front of it in the fields pane.
That's another way of
getting it into the pie chart.
Let's go ahead and save our file
and then we'll get into some formatting
of this pie chart that we just created.
The first thing I wanna
draw your attention to
is if you hover your mouse
over any of the pie slices,
you'll see the value and
percentage associated with that slice.
That is known as a tool tip.
Whatever fields you
use in the visualization
will automatically show up in the
tool tips but you can add other fields,
other pertinent information you'd like to
see when you hover over a slice of the pie.
If you'll notice in the
visualizations pane,
you're in what's called
right now the fields
well, those two boxes
with the yellow underline.
If you hover over it, it will say fields.
For a pie chart, you get legend,
details, values and tool tips fields.
Depending on the visualization type, that
will change in the visualizations pane.
What we wanna do is over in
the fields pane, we want to find
two different fields and we're
gonna add them to tool tips.
Again, the fields that you're
using in the visualization
automatically show up
as tool tips when you hover
although they don't
show in the tool tips field.
In the fields pane, find
regular sales dollars
in the sales table and drag
that field to the tool tips box.
Also find markdown sales dollars
and drag it into the tool tips box
and you can drag it
underneath regular sales dollars.
Now when you hover over a slice,
you'll see the markdown sales units.
That's the red slice I'm hovering over.
That is the field that we
used in the visualization
and you'll also now see regular
sales dollars and markdown
sales dollars because we
added those fields to tool tips.
Now we wanna apply some
formatting to our pie chart.
Specifically, we'll have a conversation
about whether we want a legend on the chart
or the detail labels that are
currently showing where it says
markdown sales units and
regular sales units on the pie chart.
We also wanna change the title
of the chart so it's more succinct.
We wanna give the chart a
background color and a shadow effect.
In order to do all of those things,
we need to get out of the fields well
in the visualizations pane
and go to the format well.
The format well is
represented by the paint roller.
So you'll notice the options
that are available here
in the format well for a
pie chart visualization.
Different types of visualizations also come
with some same and
different formatting options.
So right now, we don't have
the legend on on the chart.
So where it says legend, you
can toggle off to on on the switch
and now you'll see underneath the title
in the left corner of
your chart is the legend.
When I have a legend on my pie chart, I
often find the detail label to be redundant.
So I decide I wanna just go with the legend
and there's another format
option for detail labels.
I'm going to turn that off
by using the toggle switch.
I'm gonna expand the title format
option by clicking the down arrow
and I want to change
what the title text says.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna click
in title text and I'm gonna do control A
to select everything that's in there
and I'm gonna just type regular sales
and mark down sales units.
And as you're typing, it's
updating the title on the chart.
You have other title formatting options.
I decide that I want the
chart title to be center aligned.
So I'm gonna click on the
second alignment button
and you'll see that it instantaneously
happens on the pie chart.
Now I'm gonna collapse
the title format category
and I'm going to expand the
background category and enable
it by using the off slider so
that it turns the feature on.
I'm gonna do the color drop down and select
a comparable color for the background
of my pie chart visualization.
The last thing we're gonna
do with the pie chart formatting
is apply a shadow effect
to it for more visual appeal.
So I'm gonna expand the
shadow format category,
enable it and I'm gonna do a
slightly darker color for the shadow.
And you'll notice there is a shadow effect
on the bottom and the
right side of the visualization.
We should probably rename
the page from page one.
That's not a very
descriptive report page name.
So I'm gonna double click on
the page one tab and I'm gonna
just type reg for regular versus
mark down and press enter.
(keyboard clicking)
Go ahead and save your file.
When you deselect your report by
clicking on a blank area of the canvas
and you go back to the format,
well, by clicking the paint roller,
you'll notice that you
have different information
than we had for the
pie chart visualization.
For example, if you
wanted to change the size
of the report page, you could expand
page size, go to the dropdown next to type.
You can choose something off the
list or custom and put in your own size.
So depending on whether a visualization
is selected, the format well will change.
And when you have multiple visualizations
on a report page, it's
important that you have
the right one selected before
you go to the format well.
We're gonna create a clustered
column chart on a different page now.
So go ahead and click the plus sign
so we can generate a new report page.
And in your visualizations pane, you
wanna find the clustered column chart
and click on the icon.
I'm gonna expand the size of the chart.
You can do this before or
after or both, doesn't matter.
And we want to use information
that is also in the sales table.
We wanna see this year's
sales, last year's sales,
the total sales variance, and
we want to see it by chain.
So what I'm gonna do is in the sales table
in the fields pane, I'm gonna
expand this year's sales.
If it's not expanded, do
the arrow in front of it.
And I'm gonna check
the box in front of value.
We want this year's sales value.
Then I'm gonna go and check
the box in front of last year's sales.
And it adds that into the clustered
column chart framework as well.
Go ahead and check the box
in front of total sales variance.
And that gets added to the chart.
Now the chain resides in a different table.
So expand your store
table in the fields pane.
And you can check the box in
front of chain, or you can click and
hold and drag chain to the axis
box in the visualizations pane.
At this point, we
decide we'd like to see
the territories as well
in our visualization.
In the visualizations pane,
we have a small multiple fields
which we did not have with
the pie chart visualization.
And the territory
resides in the store table.
So in that table, I'm gonna grab territory
and drag it into the small multiples box.
And I'm gonna expand the size of my chart.
Notice it now has a scroll bar in it.
In order to see all of the
data, you would have to scroll.
And we decide we don't want
to have to scroll in this chart.
So we're not gonna put
territory in small multiples.
We decide that we're
gonna add it as a filter.
In your small multiples
box to the right of
territory, go ahead and
click the X to remove it.
In Power BI, you can
filter a report visualization
by a field that you are not
using in the visualization.
What we're gonna do is if your filters
pane is collapsed, go ahead and expand it.
And in the fields pane, right click
on the territory field in the store table.
Hover over add to filters, and you'll notice
there are three different choices there.
Visual level filters will only apply
to the visualization that's selected.
In our case, the clustered column chart.
Page level filters will apply to all
visualizations on a single report page.
And report level filters apply to all
visualizations on all report pages.
We're gonna select visual level filters.
So we only want it to apply
to this particular visualization.
In your filters pane, it
already has chain and last
year's sales, this year's
sales and total sales variance.
They're all set to show everything is all.
And those are the fields that
we're using on the visualization.
We're not using territory,
but it allows us to filter by it.
So in that filter box for territory, I'm
gonna just check the box in front of Georgia.
And you'll notice now that the visualization
is only showing information for Georgia.
I'm gonna uncheck Georgia
and it's back to the way it was
where everything, it's
showing all of the territories.
When we created our
KPI in a previous module,
we had to sort it before
we turned it into a KPI.
We decide that we wanna sort
our clustered column chart here.
We wanna sort it by this
year's sales in ascending order.
So sorting can be a two-step process.
In the upper right corner
of your visualization,
you'll see the more
options ellipsis button.
You're gonna click on
that, hover over sort by
and click on this year's sales.
Then you're gonna go back
to the more options button
and you're gonna click on sort ascending.
So now the visualization is sorted in
ascending order by this year's sales.
We decide that we wanna
add data labels to this chart.
That wasn't an option in the
format well for the pie chart.
So in your visualizations
pane, we're gonna go ahead and
click on the paint roller
to get into the format well.
And you can enable data labels by
clicking on the off slider so they're on.
Now you can see the value of each column
in our visualization.
That's what a data label does.
Take a few moments and
go ahead and format this chart
with the background color of
your choice and a shadow effect.
We're gonna name this
report page TY for this
year, comma, LY for
last year and variance
and press enter so it accepts that change.
Go ahead and save your file.
At this point, we decide that
we're never really gonna have
to filter this particular
visualization by territory.
So we're gonna remove the
territory filter from the filters pane.
Again, territory is not a field that
we're using on this visualization.
So it will allow us to remove
it from the filters pane.
The ones that are on the visualization,
you cannot remove from the filters pane.
If you hover over territory,
the top, it's title bar, to the
right, you'll see the X that will
allow you to remove that filter.
We decide instead that
we would like to be able
to filter this visualization by
chain as well as the visualization
on the reg versus markdown
report page and the KPI report page.
We'd like to use a visual
filter known as a slicer.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna make room for the slicer.
On this page, I'm gonna just
leave more space on the right
side where I'll be able to
pop the slicer visualization in.
And since we're gonna
wanna use the same slicer
on two other report pages,
KPI and reg versus markdown,
go to each of those pages and
leave about the same amount
of space on the right
side of those visualizations.
When you're done making those adjustments,
come back to your TYLY and variants page.
Make sure your
visualization is not selected.
You can click in a blank space on the
canvas to make sure it's de-selected.
And in your visualizations pane,
you're gonna find and select
the slicer visualization icon.
It looks like a table with a funnel on it.
And it popped the slicer over
on the right side of the screen.
If it didn't place it there,
you can move it over there.
And now what we're gonna do,
in the store table in the fields pane,
we're gonna just drag
chain over to the slicer.
And we realize the slicer
doesn't have to be that tall.
So I'm gonna resize it.
Doesn't need to take up that much space.
And I decide that I'm gonna do a
little bit of formatting to this slicer.
With the slicer selected, I'm going to
the format well in the visualizations pane.
And I'm gonna just enable a
background color for the slicer,
expand background and
choose a complimentary color.
I'm also fond of putting
borders around slicers,
just so they stand out a
little bit more on the page.
So I've collapsed the
background format option,
and I'm gonna enable
border and expand it.
And I'm gonna leave the
border black, but I'm gonna
make it about 30 pixels
in radius so it stands out.
And now when I click away from the
slicer, you'll see the border around it.
Let's test the slicer
on this page before we
sync and make it visible
on the other two pages.
So in the slicer, I'm gonna just
check the box in front of fashions direct,
and it filtered the
visualization for that chain.
I'm gonna uncheck that box
so I get both chains showing.
Now with your slicer still selected, you're
gonna go up to the View tab of the ribbon.
And the last button on the
View tab is Sync Slicers.
You really don't have to sync slicers.
If you want a slicer
just on one report page
and only functional on one
report page, you can do that.
But in our case, we wanna use
the same slicer on multiple pages.
When you click on Sync Slicers,
you get a Sync Slicers pane
in between your Filters and
Visualizations panes on the right side.
It will show you all of the
pages in this particular report file.
And there are two columns.
The column with the circular arrow
that represents whether
the slicer is gonna be synced.
So if it's on this page and
I sync it with another page,
that means that when I filter on this page,
the other page will be filtered as well.
And vice versa.
The other column looks
like an eye, and that's
whether the slicer will be
visible on the other pages.
So notice the slicer is already visible.
It's already checked.
This is the page that we created it on.
And we're also gonna check the
Sync button after T-Y-L-Y invariant.
So it's synced and visible on this page.
We're gonna select both check boxes
for the Reg versus Markdown page.
And we're gonna select
both for the KPI page.
And usually when you
sync it, a new update has
it automatically checking
that it's also visible.
But if that's not happening, you
will have to click both check boxes.
So what does that do?
At this point, we don't need
Sync Slicers pane open.
So to get rid of some of the clutter, I'm
gonna close that pane by using the X.
And on T-Y-L-Y invariants page,
I'm gonna go ahead and use the slicer
to filter for the Lindsay's chain.
When I go to the Reg versus Markdown
page, you'll notice the slicer is visible,
and this page is also
filtered for Lindsay's.
On this page, uncheck Lindsay's
and filter for Fashions Direct.
And when you go to your KPI
page, you'll notice the numbers
have changed as it's only
filtered for Fashions Direct.
If I go back to T-Y-L-Y invariants page,
that is also filtered for Fashions Direct.
So I'm gonna clear the filter by just
unchecking Fashions Direct in the slicer.
And now, if you look at
the other two pages, they're
showing all of the data, not
just by a particular change.
In this next lesson, we're gonna
focus on creating a drill-through page.
With drill-through in Power BI reports,
you can create a page in your report
that focuses on a specific entity,
such as a category store or territory.
When your report readers use drill-through,
they right-click a data
point in other report pages
and drill-through to the focus page to get
details that are filtered to that context.
You'll see this play out in this lesson.
We're gonna put our drill-through
report on a separate page,
so I'm gonna go ahead and click
the plus sign to get a new page,
and I'm gonna double-click page
one and name the page drill-through.
Remember to press enter after you finish
typing in the name so it accepts the name.
For this type of report
that we're gonna build,
we're gonna use the
multi-row card visualization.
In your visualizations pane, locate
the multi-row card icon and click it.
We're gonna use three fields from
the sales table to populate this card.
The first field we're gonna use
is last year's sales, so I'm gonna
just click and hold and drag it
over into the card framework.
I'm gonna grab the value field from
this year's sales and drag it over.
And the last field is we
want total sales VAR percent.
Once I drag that into the card,
I'm gonna widen the card so
it only displays one row, and
I don't need it to be that tall,
so I'm gonna make it less
tall by using the sizing handles.
At the bottom of the visualization pane,
regardless of the type
of visualization that
you select, you have
a drill-through section.
We're gonna use that section now
to add a field as a drill-through field,
and then you'll see what
happens with our visualization.
We wanna use the category
field from the item table as our
drill-through field, so I'm
gonna locate it in the fields pane.
I'm gonna click and
hold and drag it to the box
that says add drill-through fields here
at the bottom of the visualizations pane.
The category field displays like
a filter in the drill-through area.
Also, on your multi-row
card, you have a back button.
That's a navigation button
that you can use to go back to
whatever report page you
performed the drill-through on.
Let's go ahead and save our file.
We'll circle back to formatting the multi-row
card, but right now, we wanna proceed
so you can see the
functionality of using drill-through.
We're gonna create a stacked
bar chart on a new page.
Go ahead and create a new page,
and name that page Sales by Category.
In your visualizations
pane, the stacked bar chart
is typically the first icon.
Go ahead and locate it and click on
it to put the framework on the canvas.
From the item table,
we're gonna drag Category
to the access box in
the visualizations pane,
and we're gonna drag from
the sales table this year's
sales value to the values
box in the visualizations pane,
and we have our stacked bar chart.
Now, I'm gonna make the
bar chart just a little bit wider,
and we'll come back and format it
later, and I'm gonna click away from it
because we wanna add
two slicers to this page,
one for chain and one for buyer.
So in your visualizations pane,
locate your slicer icon and click on it,
and I'm gonna just move the slicer
over to the right side of the canvas.
It doesn't need to be as wide as it is,
and you can size yours accordingly.
So I'm gonna just pop
it over here on the right
side, and you'll notice
the red dashed lines.
Those are like your guides
when you're trying to align things.
So when the line is on the bottom,
it means it's aligned with
the bottom of the visualization,
and I'm gonna go to the store table
and drag chain into the slicer,
and we decide that we want the slicer,
instead of having everything displayed
like it is now with the two check
boxes, we want it to be a drop-down.
So to the right of chain,
you'll see the drop-down arrow.
It says select the type of slicer,
and we're gonna choose drop-down.
So now when you do the drop-down, it defaults
to all, and you'll see the two choices.
This is a particularly useful tip when
you have a lot of entries in the slicer,
instead of having to have a long, long
slicer, you can just make it into a drop-down.
We'll do more formatting on
the slicer as well a little bit later.
Right now I'm gonna click
on the blank area of the
canvas, and I'm gonna
grab the slicer icon again.
I'm gonna size it down,
and I'm going to move it over
to the right of the chain slicer.
And this time, in the item table, I'm
gonna drag buyer into the new slicer.
Make that one a drop-down as well.
(mouse clicking)
And for right now, I'm gonna just
move the buyer one down a little bit.
We're gonna go ahead and save our file,
and then we'll explore
how to use drill-through.
Let's go back to the drill-through page
and take a look at last year's
sales, 23 million and change.
We can navigate back to sales by category.
If we right-click on any
of these data points, so we
have men's, shoes, these
are the different categories,
now that we have a drill-through page,
we'll see drill-through
on the right-click menu.
So what I'm gonna do, and it
even tells you that when you
hover over a category, it
says right-click to drill-through.
I'm gonna hover over
shoes and right-click on it,
hover over drill-through,
and it shows the target page.
I'm gonna click on drill-through,
and now when I look at this data, it's
only representing the shoe category.
If you look at the bottom
of the visualization pane,
you'll see it's as if
you filtered it for shoes.
So the numbers reflect that.
You can use the back
button, the back arrow.
If you hold down your
control key and click
it, it will take you back
to your source page.
We're gonna filter this report by a buyer.
So I'm gonna go to the dropdown next to all
in the buyer slicer, and I'm gonna
check the box in front of Barrett Galvin.
So now this report has updated.
It's just showing his sales.
I'm gonna right-click on
the women's category,
hover over drill-through,
and click on drill-through,
and now we'll see last year's sales
are blank, and we have this year's sales.
So Galvin didn't sell anything last year.
He's not responsible for, as a buyer,
of buying anything that sold last year.
He may have just started
with the company this year.
But I wanna draw your attention
to the drill-through section now.
When it was filtered by category,
which is the field we use as our drill-through
field, it looks like a regular filter.
And you can see now
that it's filtered for women's.
That's what we right-clicked on.
Underneath that, we have another
filter, and this one is in italics.
That's because it's
not a drill-through field.
We use the buyer slicer
on the source report,
so it appears different in
the drill-through section.
We're gonna use the back button
to go back to our source report.
We're gonna do the buyer slicer
dropdown and uncheck Barrett Galvin,
so we get the full information
back in this visualization.
Now we're gonna spend a little bit of time
formatting the drill-through
and sales by category reports.
Let's start with the drill-through page.
Now even though we cleared
the buyer slicer on the source page,
sales by category, you'll notice
that the data hasn't updated.
You have to clear it on your
drill-through report page as well.
So in the bottom of the visualizations pane,
we're gonna clear the women's category.
Now you can either uncheck it or you can use
the little eraser that says clear filter.
And then underneath that,
we have the buyer filter is
still there, even though
we cleared the buyer slicer,
and we're gonna do the
X to just remove that filter.
So now we have our full number set back.
Make sure your multi-row
card visualization is selected,
and we're gonna go over to the paint roller
in the visualizations pane
to go back to the format well.
We don't need data labels.
We're seeing the numbers.
It's a multi-row card, right?
We don't want to put a title on the card.
Maybe we do wanna give the card
a border for some visual interest.
So I'm gonna toggle border
to on and expand the category,
and I'm gonna give it a
border color like a bluish color.
And I'm gonna make
the border 30 pixel radius,
and when I click away from
the card, I can see the effect.
It's a little bit more visually appealing.
I'm gonna reselect the card
and go back to the format well,
and I decide I'm gonna give
the card a background color.
So I'm gonna toggle background
to on, expand the category,
and I'm gonna choose a lighter color,
and I'm gonna click away from the card.
In terms of the arrow that comes
when you do a drill through page,
you can actually swap that out
for something else of your choice.
It's actually a second component.
It's kinda sorta on its
own outside of the card.
So if you click on the arrow,
you'll notice that it selects just that.
You'll see the sizing handles around that,
and you can press Delete on your keyboard,
and we're gonna use another
back arrow for our back button.
So what we're gonna want to do is
go up to the Insert tab of the ribbon,
and the last group is the Elements group.
You can insert a text box on a
visualization page, a variety of buttons.
If you look at the buttons,
you'll see the back button.
That's the one that came as a default
when we created this drill through page,
and they have other arrow buttons in here.
We can use an image if
it's stored on your computer.
What we're gonna use is shapes.
So under Shapes, they have block arrows,
and we're gonna select
the arrow left block arrow.
Puts it in pretty big, so I'm
gonna make it really tiny.
And I am going to move
it so that it is right above
my multi-row card.
And with the block arrows still selected,
you'll notice you have another pane.
You have a Format Shape pane that shows up
where the Visualizations pane used to be.
And in that pane, you
have an Action option.
We're gonna enable the
Action option and then expand it,
and you'll see that the default action
is that it serves as a back button,
just like the one that
came when we did this
visualization and
made it a drill through.
You have other choices there.
We're gonna leave it on Back.
And now I'm gonna just
click away from the arrow,
hold down my Control key,
and click on it, and it should
take me back to the Sales
by Category report page.
Go ahead and save your file.
Spend a few moments in the format well, and
give your stacked bar chart data labels,
add a background color, and
a shadow effect if you'd like.
We want to apply the same
formatting to both of our slicers,
so there's a time-saving
technique that you can use.
I'm gonna click at the very top of the
chain slicer, hold down my Control key,
and click at the top of the buyer
slicer so both of them are selected.
In the format well, with
both slicers already selected,
I'm gonna expand Selection Controls, and
make sure Select All option is toggled to On.
I'm gonna collapse Selection Controls,
and I'm gonna expand the background,
and choose a background color that's
complementary to the rest of the page.
So see how it impacts
both slicers at the same time.
Because I chose a dark background color,
I'm gonna expand Items,
and change the item color,
the font color for the items, to white,
so they show up a little bit better.
I'm gonna click on a blank area
of the canvas to deselect both
of those slicers, and I just
need to resize my buyer slicer
so it's the same size as the
chain one for consistency.
Go ahead and save your file.
Just like Excel, Power BI has
a conditional formatting feature.
Let's navigate to our
TYLY and Variants page,
and the first thing we're
gonna do is resize the column
chart visualization so
it's not as tall as it is.
We're gonna wanna
put another visualization
underneath it, so we're
just making space for that.
Conditional formatting
in Power BI lends itself
to the table visualization,
or the matrix visualization.
In the visualization pane,
we're gonna make sure
that we don't have anything
selected on our canvas,
and we're gonna select
the table visualization icon.
From the sales table in the fields pane,
we're gonna wanna add
last year's sales to the table,
so I'm gonna just drag it
into the table framework,
and we're also going to wanna add
this year's sales value into the table.
So we just have two columns in the table,
and that's fine for what we're trying to do.
So in order to do conditional
formatting, you have to
access the field that you
want to conditionally format
from the visualizations pane.
So if you notice, we have last year's sales
and this year's sales in the values box.
We wanna conditionally
format this year's sales.
So I'm gonna right-click on
this year's sales, hover over
conditional formatting, and I'm
gonna click on background color.
So the background
color for the specific field
that we right-click on, this year's sale,
dialog box comes up on the screen.
Take a moment and explore
the format by dropdown.
We're gonna leave it on color scale,
but you do have other options there.
And also take a look at
the apply to dropdown that's
defaulting to values only, and
we're gonna leave it like that.
It tells you it's based on this
field, and that's also a dropdown,
so you could search for
other fields from in here
if you happen to right-click
on the wrong field.
We have a minimum and maximum area,
and before we start
filling in any numbers
here, we're gonna check
the diverging checkbox.
So now we have minimum,
center, and maximum areas to fill out.
The scenario we're using
here is we wanna say that we
have a tolerance for what
this year's sales should be.
We're comfortable with
a minimum of 20 million.
We would like to have
a maximum of 25 million,
and we're kinda okay in the center
if the center is $23,500,000.
So we're gonna start putting
those numbers in boxes.
Under minimum, where it says enter a
value, you're gonna put in your 20 million,
for the center enter a
value box, it's gonna be 23.
5 million, and the maximum
is going to be 25 million.
Before we click okay, let's take
a look at this year's sales value.
22,051,952.
So it's not at the minimum,
certainly not at the maximum.
It's a little bit below center.
So when you're diverging,
there is a color scale there.
If we were directly at
center, it would be this
yellowish color, but we're
a little bit less than center.
So go ahead and click okay,
and look at the color that it used
to highlight this year's sales.
Now keep in mind, if our data changes,
if we add more sales for
this year to our data set, that
color on this year's sales will
change accordingly as well.
That's an example of a conditional format.
Another useful efficiency technique
is using the bookmarks
feature in your Power BI reports.
Let's go to the sales by category page.
And the first thing we
have to do is let's go to
where the dropdown
would be in the buyer slicer.
And remember, we changed
the item color, the font
color to white, so we're
not able to see the items.
I neglected to have you change the
background of the items to a darker color.
So I'm gonna click on
the chain slicer to select it,
hold down my control key
and click on the buyer slicer,
and go to the paint roller
to get into the format well.
I'm gonna expand items
and do the dropdown next to
background color, and I'm
gonna choose a dark color.
If I click on the blank area of the
canvas and go to the buyer all dropdown,
I'll be able to see all of the
buyers names clearly now
because it's a contrasting
background color.
We're gonna select Evangeline Bright.
So now our chart is filtered
for just Evangeline Bright.
Let's say that this report page you come to
often and you filter for different buyers.
You can save your filtered
report as a bookmark.
To do that, you're gonna go
up to the view tab on the ribbon
in the show panes group, the last
group, you're gonna click on bookmarks,
and it opens a panel to the
left of your visualization pane.
With the report filtered for
Evangeline Bright, the way it is,
we're gonna click add at the
top of the bookmarks pane,
and it adds a bookmark,
it calls it bookmark one.
To the right of it, we're
gonna go to the more
options ellipsis, and we're
gonna choose rename,
and we'll just call it Evangeline Bright,
the buyer's name, and press enter.
Now go ahead and close your bookmarks pane
by using the X in the
upper right hand corner.
Access the buyer slicer dropdown,
and choose select all at the top.
The next time that you wanna
see it filtered for Evangeline Bright,
you don't actually have to do the filter,
you just need to access the bookmark.
We're gonna go back to
bookmarks on the view tab,
and in the bookmarks pane, you're
gonna click on Evangeline Bright,
and it does the same filter for you.
So imagine if you set up a bookmark for
those buyers that you wanna track frequently,
you can have multiple bookmarks set
up and access them anytime you need to.
Go ahead and save your file.
And you can close the bookmarks pane,
and do your buyer slicer dropdown
again, and go back to select all.
Our next lesson is about accessibility
features in Power BI reports.
There are two main
categories of features, built-in
accessibility features that
require no configuration,
and built-in accessibility
features requiring configuration.
The features that don't require
configuration are keyboard navigation.
A lot of users want to navigate using
their keyboard through the reports.
There's screen reader compatibility.
If you have high contrast
colors set in Windows,
those high contrast
colors will come over
into Power BI reports and
be applied to your reports.
You have focus mode so
you can fill up the whole canvas
and just focus on the
visualization that you're looking at.
And another one that requires no configuration
is the ability to show a data table
of the underlying data for
that particular visualization.
You'll get to see some of these
as we go through this lesson.
We also have features
that do require configuration.
In this lesson, we'll go through alt
text, which is text that a screen reader
will read out to the user, making
sure that the tab order is appropriate,
especially for those users that want to
navigate a report by using the keyboard.
There are titles and labels that
can be configured as well as markers,
and you'll get to see
some of the report themes.
The first thing we're
gonna do is configure alt text
for our bar chart on the
sales by category page.
So I've just selected the chart,
and I am gonna go to the format well
in the visualizations
pane and expand general.
If you scroll down, you'll see alt text
at the bottom of the general category.
So if you don't put in alt text,
any screen reader will give
a generic description of whatever
object the end user selects.
So let it just give it
a generic description.
You wanna give a more detailed description.
So in that alt text box, you're
gonna say, you're gonna actually type,
this is a bar graph
representing this year's sales.
Broken down by category.
So when the screen reader
responds to this selected
visualization, that
is the text it will read.
Another accessibility feature
that needs to be configured
via a shortcut key combination is the ability
to add a data table to a visualization.
A data table shows the
underlying data in a table format
that's causing the
visualization to be drawn.
So with that same bar chart selected,
the shortcut key combination for
adding a data table is alt shift F11.
And when you do it, you'll notice
on the bottom half of the screen,
it has a table, a data
table showing a listing
of the categories and each
category sales for this year.
That can be useful when
someone needs to review a report.
You'll notice at the top, it
has a back to report button.
And when you click that button,
it just gets rid of the data table
and takes you back to
the regular report page.
Another useful feature
available for every report
visualization is the ability
to go into focus mode.
In the upper right hand
corner of the bar report,
you'll see the middle
button is focus mode.
I'm gonna click on it.
And this is similar to the type of screen
you get when you put in a data table.
It just doesn't have the data table.
It makes sure that
the visualization fills up
the screen so you can
direct your focus to that.
We're gonna click the back to report
button, again, to get back to the report.
An equally important feature
to consider is the tab order.
For those users that are gonna be using the
keyboard to navigate through the report,
you wanna make sure
that the tab order is correct.
Go ahead and press the tab key on your
keyboard and it should select the bar graph.
When you press tab again, it
should go to the chain slicer.
And when you press it again,
it should go to the buyer slicer.
Let's say for some reason, you
don't want it to land on the chain slicer.
Maybe you don't want end users to
be able to filter by chain on this report.
Or if the tab order is out
of order, you need to fix it.
Both are found in the same place.
On the view tab of the ribbon,
in the show panes group,
you're gonna click on selection
and it opens the selection pane.
At the top, you can look at
the layer order or tab order.
Click on tab order.
So we're seeing the tab order here.
It's saying the first thing it's gonna go
to is the slicer that we're currently on.
And then the second
thing is the second slicer
and we wanna change the order here.
So to ensure that it goes to the bar graph
first, I'm clicking on the number three
and I'm gonna use the up arrow
to move it to the first position.
I'm gonna click on the number two and say
that should be moved to the last position.
No, we'll leave that one second.
And for the third one, we actually really
don't want this one to be in the tab order.
We'll leave it there for right now.
An equally important feature to
consider is the tab order on a report page.
I'm still on the sales by category page
and I'm gonna press the
tab key on my keyboard
and you'll notice that
it is selecting the bar
chart, this year's sale
by category bar chart.
When I press tab again,
it goes over to the buyer
slicer and again, it
goes to the chain slicer.
So the tab order is not
correct, it should flow.
And for people that are
accessing your report, using their
keyboard to navigate it, tab order
becomes particularly important.
So I'm gonna show you where we would
go to make sure the tab order is correct.
It's going to be on the
view tab of the ribbon
in that last group again,
you're gonna click selection
and it opens the selection pane.
At the top of the pane,
it defaults to layer order
and to the right, you're
gonna click on tab order.
So we wanna make
sure this year's sales by
category is in position
number one, which it is.
I'm gonna click on number two
slicer and that's the buyer slicer
and I want that to be in the last position.
So I'm gonna go above
the names of the objects
and I'm gonna click the down
arrow button to move that one down.
Now, when I test my tab order,
I'm gonna just click anywhere
on the canvas of my report,
press my tab key and
it selects the bar chart,
press it again, it selects chain
and again, it selects buyer.
I'm gonna go ahead and close
the selection pane and save my file.
The last accessibility
feature we're gonna cover
in this module is the use
of a theme, one in particular.
So on the view tab, you
have a gallery of themes
and we're gonna access it by
using the dropdown arrow to the right.
Under Power BI, there is a theme
and when you hover over them,
you'll see the screen tip
showing you the names.
In my screen, it's in the second
row and it's second column
under Power BI, there is a
theme called colorblind safe.
I'm gonna go ahead and
click on that theme and apply it.
When you choose a
theme, it supersedes any
formatting that you've
done on the report pages.
So if you go to your drill through page,
you'll see that that has the
same colorblind friendly theme.
Other report pages has it as well.
There are also themes available
to you in the online service
and you'll see that in the next module.
Our next lesson is how to
create a histogram visualization.
The histogram visualization does not
default to being in the visualizations pane.
It's a visualization that
you're gonna have to add.
So in order to do that, let's go
over to our visualizations pane
and after the last
visualization, you'll see the
vertical ellipsis icon and
it says get more visuals.
We're gonna click on that and
then click on get more visuals.
When you do this, it brings
you into Power BI visuals
and it defaults to the app source
tab at the top of the dialogue box.
You also have a my organization tab.
So your Power BI admin can add
visuals for the entire organization
and when that happens, you can
access them from the my organization tab.
We're gonna go back to the app source tab.
You'll notice they have
categories of visualizations
and we can click in the
search box and type histogram
and when you press enter
or click the search button,
the magnifying glass, it will
show you the histogram chart.
There's a couple of different kinds
in here from the app source store.
We want the default histogram chart so we're
gonna click the add button on the right
and depending on your licensing, you may
not have the ability to get more visuals.
It will let you know that it
imported this custom visual
successfully and I'm gonna
click okay on that dialogue.
So the histogram icon shows up
underneath all of the other visualizations.
If we were to open a
new Power BI desktop file,
the histogram visualization
icon will not be there.
If you want it to retain over
different files, you need to pin it.
So I'm gonna right click on that histogram
icon and choose pin to visualizations pane
and it will ultimately move it up
so it's amongst all the other
visualizations in that pane.
Now that we've pinned the histogram
visualization icon to our visualizations pane,
we're gonna start a
new Power BI desktop file
and bring in information
from an Excel file.
I'm gonna go to the file tab
on the ribbon and choose new
so it will launch a new
instance of Power BI desktop
and because you
pinned the histogram
visualization, it shows
up in the new file as well.
On your splash screen,
we're gonna click on get data
and when the dialogue
box opens on the right
side, we're gonna double
click Excel workbook
and we're gonna use
the histogram Excel file
that you grabbed from
the video description earlier.
I'm gonna just double
click it and let it connect
and this file only has one sheet
in it called employee salaries.
I'm gonna click the check mark
and you'll see it just
has generic employee
data and their monthly
salaries in dollars.
We're gonna click the
load button at the bottom.
This data is ideal for a histogram
and you'll see why in just a moment.
Let's take a look at the data in data view.
So it just shows the
generic employee identifiers
and their monthly salary in dollars.
The reason why this is
good data for a histogram
because a histogram is a
representation of data points into ranges.
Data points are grouped into
ranges or bins is what they're
called in a histogram, making
the data more understandable.
So what we're gonna do
is go back to report view
and we have this blank page here.
Let's go ahead and rename page one.
So it's called histogram
and the first thing we're gonna do
is create a table visualization
using the employee salaries data.
So in your visualizations pane,
find your table icon and click on it.
Expand your employee
salaries table in the field pane
and we wanna do the employee,
drag the employee field into the table
and then drag monthly
salary in dollars into the table.
So just in a table format,
we're able to see this information
and what's gonna happen is
when we put this information
into a histogram, it's gonna
do groupings of employees
known as bins based
on their monthly salary.
So for example, it may create
a bin for the count of employees
that are in the salary
range of say 2,000 to 2,500.
Another bin would be 2,501
to 3,000, so on and so forth
and you'll see this play out right now.
Go ahead and press delete
to delete the table visualization
and in your visualizations pane, you're gonna
click on your newly added histogram icon
and you can go ahead
and expand the width and
height if you'd like of
the histogram framework
and if we look in the
visualizations pane, you'll notice that
we have a values field and a
frequency field for the histogram.
We're gonna use the monthly salary field
from employee salaries
table as the values field
and we're gonna use the
employee as the frequency field
and when you drag employee
into the frequency field,
it says first employee, we
want a count of employees.
So we're gonna do the
dropdown arrow next to
first employee and we're
gonna click on count.
So what you're looking at, I'm
gonna just make my histogram bigger.
So the frequency is over on the
left and we're gonna format that
so it doesn't have any
decimal points in a few moments
but what's happening is it
created, these are your bins.
So it did groupings of the salaries.
So you have 2.02,000
through, that's the beginning
of the first bin.
The second bin begins with 2.51,000.
The third one is 3.00,000,
so on and so forth.
So when you hover over
a bin, which is a column
in the histogram, you
can see the frequency.
So that's saying there are 25
employees that fit into that first bin
and it gives you the range of the bin.
That is what a histogram does.
Now we wanna format that axis on
the left, which is known as the X axis,
the one on the bottom is known as the
Y axis, to get rid of the decimal places.
So I'm gonna just go to the format well
and I'm gonna expand X axis
and where it says decimal places two,
I'm gonna change the two to a zero and press
enter and I did that on the wrong axis.
So I'm gonna change that
back to two decimal places.
I do this all the time
and I'm gonna collapse the
X axis and expand the Y axis.
I always get them backwards and
change the two for decimal places to zero
and now you can see the
change for the frequency.
Doesn't need decimal
places over there, it's a count.
Go ahead and we're gonna close this file.
If you wanna keep it, you can
save it and just call it histogram.
So I'm gonna go ahead and do save
and it'll prompt me and to give it a name
and I'm gonna call it histogram
and then I am going to close it
and you still have your retail
analysis sample file open.
I mentioned earlier that another
way to get great report ideas
is by viewing reports that have
been created by other people.
We have lots of them
in this particular file.
Let's go to the overview page
and if you see a report
that someone else
designed that you like,
you can select the report.
So I'm gonna select, let's
see, we'll select the total
sales variance percent report
in the lower right hand corner
and when I look in the visualizations pane,
I'm gonna go ahead and
collapse the fields pane for now.
When I look in the visualizations
pane, I can see which
visual was selected, in
this case, a scatter chart.
So if I wanted to recreate this,
I know that I can by using
a scatter chart visualization.
I also have all of the fields that
were used and where they were used.
So we have district and store
number in the details section,
we have district and the
legend, so on and so forth.
So I can use that information to recreate
this type of chart and I can even
use different fields when I recreate it.
The easiest way of doing
this is copying the visualization.
When you copy a visualization, you
can only copy it within Power BI Desktop.
So from one report page to another.
You can't copy it
outside of the application.
What we're gonna do
is we're gonna right click
in a blank area of that
visualization in the lower left
and we're gonna hover over
copy and choose copy visual.
Let's do the plus sign to create a new page
and click anywhere on the canvas and you're
gonna do control V as in Victor to paste.
So now we have this visual on its own page
and we can go over to the visualizations
pane and swap out fields if we want to.
We're going to delete the page
that we just pasted the visual on.
So I'm right clicking on page
one, choosing delete page.
It will always confirm
if you want a deletion.
Go ahead and confirm the deletion.
Save your file.
In this extensive module,
you learned how to design,
enhance, configure, and
format report visualizations,
how to create and configure sync slicers,
how to create a drill through page,
apply conditional formatting
on a field in a visualization,
create and use bookmarks for
efficiency, how to create a histogram,
and we reviewed some accessibility
options in the reporting module.
Now that we've created and
assembled our report pages,
we're ready to move on to module
eight, which is creating dashboards.
Once you put your data
together on a dashboard,
it gives you the opportunity to give
a compelling story about your data.
You'll also learn
about the features and
functionality of dashboards
and how to enhance them.
We'll be using the sample
SuperStore OD dataset
that we published to the
Power BI service in module two,
as well as the Microsoft Forms and
Power Automate apps in this module.
You can access those apps by
logging into your Microsoft account,
going to the waffle in
the upper left-hand corner,
and you should see all the
apps that you have access to.
We'll start this module
by creating a dashboard
by pinning visualizations
to it in the Power BI service.
We'll move on to real-time dashboards where
the visualizations update in real time
because we'll be accessing
a real-time dataset,
and we'll also get to use a form and the
Power Automate feature during that lesson.
We'll go into enhancing a dashboard,
which could mean adding a
video to it, text box, a theme.
We're gonna configure
a dashboard tile alert,
so if changes happen to that
dashboard tile, you can be alerted,
and we'll use a feature named Q&A
for analysis to finish off this module.
Dashboards are not created in the desktop.
They're created in the service.
As mentioned, they can
contain report visualizations,
videos, text boxes,
audio files, and web
content, including other
dashboards or reports.
You can share dashboards,
have conversations
about them, both in
the service or in Teams.
You can even subscribe yourself and others
to email alerts regarding dashboards.
You'll learn how to do all of
those things during this module.
We'll start by navigating
to the Power BI workspace
where we publish the Sample
Superstore OD report and dataset.
We're gonna get started by accessing
the Sample Superstore OD report
that we publish to the
service in module two.
First thing I wanna point out here
is the difference in icons.
When we publish from
the desktop to the service,
it published both the
report, which has a blue icon,
and it looks like a column chart on
it, and it also published the dataset,
which has an orange icon, and
it looks like a database icon on it.
We want to access the report,
so Sample Superstore OD is
a link, and we're gonna click it.
And it will navigate us to the report.
So this was a simple report that we put
together earlier, and we're gonna edit it.
We wanna add three visualizations to it,
and we can really get rid of
the visualization that's on it.
So once you have published to the service,
if there are any changes to your reports,
or even if you wanna create new
ones, you can do it in the service.
And the way that you do
that is by coming up here
to the menu and clicking
the More Options button.
Choose Edit.
And this view should
look very familiar to you.
It's almost exactly the same as
Report View in Power BI Desktop.
So you have your Fields and Visualizations
and Filters pane on the right.
Let's start by clicking on
the blank area of the canvas,
and we're gonna wanna
add another visualization here.
And so we're gonna use
the Table Visualization.
Find it in your Visualizations pane.
And we're gonna expand the
Orders table in the Fields pane.
And we wanna add Customer
Segment field to our table.
The other field that we
wanna add to the table is Sales.
So in our table, we're seeing
Customer Segment by Sales.
And we can go ahead and resize that table.
Doesn't need to be as big as it is
to show that little amount of data.
Before we add our other two
visualizations, let's go ahead
and select the bar chart
that was already on this page,
and press Delete on your
keyboard to get rid of it.
I'm gonna then move the table
up to where the bar chart was.
So it's in like the upper
left-hand corner of the page.
And I'm gonna click
on the blank area of the
canvas again before I
add my next visualization.
Let's grab the Stacked
Bar Chart Visualization,
and we're gonna use the same two
fields in it that we used in the table.
So go ahead and check Customer
Segment in the Fields pane and check Sales.
We're gonna click on the
blank area of the canvas.
And the last visualization we're
gonna add is the Card Visualization.
And we want to just have
that show the total sales.
I'm gonna move the Card Visualization
so it's to the right of the table.
And you can see the
same red guidelines that
are there as when you're
in Power BI Desktop.
These three visualizations are defaulting
to interact with each other by filtering.
So in the table, if I click on Consumer,
you'll notice that the card updates
to just show the sales for
the Consumer Segment.
And that the bar chart also updates.
I'm gonna just click on the
blank area of the canvas.
And now we want to save this report.
And you can do that from the File
dropdown and just choose Save.
We won't worry about any
formatting on this report right now.
The greater picture is to
get it onto a dashboard.
Now we're ready to create a
dashboard by pinning this report to it.
On the Task pane going
across the top of your screen,
you'll notice there's an icon
that says Pin to a Dashboard.
We're gonna go ahead and click that icon
and it opens the Pin to the Dashboard box.
If you have existing dashboards in here,
it will list them in alphabetical order.
We're gonna create a new dashboard
and we're gonna name it Sample Superstore.
And then we're gonna
click the Pin Live button.
And it tells you Pin Live
page enables changes
to reports to appear in the dashboard
tile when the page is refreshed.
So we're gonna go ahead
and click on Pin Live.
And it tells us it pinned
it to a dashboard.
And if you catch that pop-up quick enough,
you can go to the
dashboard from that pop-up.
If you don't catch it
quick enough, you can get
to the dashboard by going
back to your workspace.
There's a couple of ways you can get
back from your report to the workspace.
You can come right up
here at the top in the title bar
and click on your
workspace or on the left side,
the next to the last button
will take you to your workspace.
Either way is fine.
When you get back to your workspace, you'll
notice that now for Sample Superstore,
we still have for OD
to report in the dataset,
but now we also have a
Sample Superstore dashboard
and just take note of the different icon.
So this one is like a greenish icon.
It looks like it has a gauge inside of it.
To get to the dashboard, we're gonna
just click on the link Sample Superstore.
And now you're seeing your dashboard.
After we create our second dashboard,
you'll learn how to enhance dashboards.
In the meantime, let's
go back to our workspace
where the dashboard resides.
And I'd like you to go back to
the Sample Superstore OD report.
Because we were in edit mode,
when we pinned it to the dashboard,
we had that huge set of
options going across the top.
What if you want to not edit a
report and just add it to a dashboard?
I figured I'd show you how
that process would work.
So that's when you would
just use more options up here
and you would have the
pin to a dashboard choice.
We've already pinned
this report to a dashboard
so we don't have to
go through that step.
Just wanted to show you how to find it when
you're not in edit mode in report view.
In this next lesson, we're gonna create a
dashboard based on streaming real-time data.
Your dashboards will update
in real time when you use
this method, and the data
can be from various sources.
We create these
real-time data sets in the
service as you'll see
play out in this lesson.
When you're using real-time
data, there are three primary
types of real-time data sets
that you can use in the service.
There are push data sets, streaming
data sets, and pub nub data sets.
Let's take a look at the differences
between the three of them
in terms of the capability
of what they can do.
We're gonna end up using a
push data set for our next example.
And also just a reminder, this PowerPoint
presentation is in the video description
so you'll be able to
refer to it in the future.
So the push data set, all of them update
in real time as the data is pushed in.
You'll notice that the push method
allows data to be stored permanently
in Power BI for historic analysis.
When it's streaming, the
data is only temporarily stored
for an hour to render visuals, and
pub nub doesn't store any data at all.
Because the data is stored
permanently for the push method,
you can use your Power
BI reports atop the data.
So we'll be using the
real-time push data set
because it creates a database
which maintains history.
We can use the Power BI
visualizations on that data.
It'll still be real-time in your
dashboard so no need to refresh.
There's a difference here.
You cannot pin live pages like
we did in our previous example.
We would have to pin each individual visual
to the dashboard in
order for it to be effective
and refresh in real time.
It's counterintuitive pinning
live and real-time refresh
so we won't be able to
use the pin live feature
that we just saw, but
you'll see how this plays out.
We're gonna start this lesson by
creating a form in Microsoft Forms
that will be used to push the data into the
data set and create the database for us.
So I've signed into my Microsoft
account and I'm in Microsoft Forms.
If you need to get yourself into Microsoft
Forms, you can use the Microsoft Waffle
in the upper left-hand
corner of your screen
and that will give you
access to all of your apps.
When you click on the Waffle,
you'll be able to see Forms in the list.
If you don't see it in the list,
you wanna click on All Apps
and then you should be able
to find it in your list of apps.
Go ahead and launch Microsoft Forms
and your screen will look similar to mine.
We're gonna create a
short three-question form
that will be used as the vehicle to push
data into the data set we're gonna create.
In the upper left corner, go ahead
and click directly on New Form.
It may ask you to pick an account.
Sometimes it even asks you to sign in.
Where it says Untitled
Form, we're gonna click
and we're gonna just
call this Streaming Survey.
We don't need to enter a
description, it is optional.
We're gonna go ahead and click the
Add New button to add our first question
and the type of response
is gonna be a choice.
So we're gonna click on Choice.
The question is, which VI technology
are you most interested in learning about?
So I'm gonna just type that
in next to the number one,
which VI technology are you
most interested in learning about?
And I'll give it a
question mark at the end.
We're gonna click where it says Option
1 and the first option is Power Apps.
Option 2 is Power Automate.
And we're gonna add another
option using the Add Option button.
And that one is going to be Power BI.
To the right of the Add Option button,
we're gonna add the Other option.
So it gives an opportunity to select Other
and put in a choice that's not on our list.
We only want them to choose one answer, so
we're not gonna toggle multiple answers on
and we're not gonna
make this question required.
Instead, we're gonna
add our second question.
So click your Add New button.
And the second question will
also be a choice, so click on Choice.
This question is,
what is your current
experience level on the
technology you selected?
What is your current experience level
on the technology you selected?
We're gonna click on Option 1,
but if you notice right above Option
1, it gives us some suggested options.
And in that list of suggested
options, we're gonna click on Beginner.
For Option 2, we're gonna
select the Preset Intermediate.
And we're gonna add an option
again, so we have three options.
In this one, we want to be Expert, and
there's a preset for that there as well.
Again, we only want one answer.
It's not a required question.
We're gonna go ahead and
Add New to get our third question.
And I got this pop up.
Every time something is
updating, they let you know.
I'm gonna just get
rid of it by doing Got It.
Has nothing to do with
what we're doing right now.
So I'm gonna go back to Add New.
And this one is going to
be a text type response.
The question here is, where are you from?
And we want to be helpful
and give them information
about the format we
want the answer to be in.
So after the question in parentheses,
I'm gonna type Provide Answer
in City, ST for State format.
And I'm gonna give an example.
For example, I'll put in San Francisco, CA.
And close my parentheses.
And so those are the three
questions that we want on this form.
The responses to these questions will
be pushed into our database in the cloud.
If you'll notice, since this is online,
the form has already been saved.
I can click back on
Forms in the upper left
corner, and I'll see my
streaming survey form.
We're gonna navigate back to our workspace
so that we can start creating
our streaming dataset.
When we switch back over to the service,
we're still seeing the
Sample Superstore OD report.
In my case, it's in my
Power BI video workspace,
and I decide I want to put our
streaming data in a new workspace.
On the left side of your screen, the
workspaces icon looks like a stack of papers.
And that's how you can start the process
of creating a new workspace.
I'm gonna go ahead and click that icon,
and at the bottom, I'm gonna
choose Create a Workspace.
So the panel opens up on the
right to create the workspace.
We're gonna name the
workspace Streaming Dataset.
So you can just type
Streaming Dataset in there.
And for the description, contains all
components of our streaming data.
If you wanted to learn more about workspace
settings, you could click this link.
It would open a new browser tab.
We're gonna go ahead
and click Save at the bottom,
and you'll notice you are in
your new Streaming Dataset.
Now we just have to create the dataset.
So we have the workspace
that's empty at this point.
We are going to create the dataset
by using the New button
on the left side of the screen.
And on that list of things, you're
gonna select Streaming Dataset.
And the panel on the right opens up.
We talked about the three
methods of getting streaming
data, real-time streaming
data into Power BI.
API is the method we're gonna use.
That's for the Push Dataset.
Streaming would be Azure
Stream, and then we have PubNub.
We're gonna leave it
on API and click on Next.
We're gonna name the dataset
Streaming Dataset just to be consistent.
They'll have different
icons, so you'll be able to tell,
and it tells you whether
it's a report versus a dataset,
so on and so forth.
For the values from the stream, we're
gonna leave all of them defaulting to text,
but go ahead and do the
dropdown next to texting.
You can see it could be
text, number, or date, time.
Our first value, we're using three values
from the survey form that we created.
So our first value is gonna be technology.
That was referenced in the first question,
so we're just gonna call
this value Technology.
And again, we're gonna leave it on text.
It's putting it in.
It's showing you some of
the behind-the-way coding.
It's a range, so we're
naming it Technology,
and it's gonna pull
whatever value is put in the
response for that question
from the form ultimately.
That data's gonna be
pushed into this dataset.
Our next value that we're gonna use here
is gonna be experience.
And the third value
is going to be location.
And you can just see that it gives
you another space for a new value.
We can ignore that.
It expanded the range,
technology, experience, location,
and underneath that, you'll
see it's historic data analysis.
By default, it is off.
We wanna toggle that on.
So it creates the database,
retains all of the data
from all of the responses from that
streaming survey form that we created.
Go ahead and click the Create button.
It lets you know that your
streaming dataset has been created.
It gives you the schema for it, right?
You're looking at the raw data
here, and it gives you a push URL.
We're gonna just go ahead and click
Done in the lower right-hand corner.
Even though we don't have any
data in our streaming dataset yet,
we're gonna go ahead and create our reports
so that when we do fill out our form
and push data into the dataset, the report
visualizations will automatically populate.
To do that, I'm gonna use the More
Options button to the right of the dataset,
and I'm gonna click on Create Report,
and it opens up the reporting
interface that you're used to.
We saw this when we
edited in the previous lesson,
and we saw this when we were
working in Power BI Desktop.
Notice in your Fields pane,
it just says Realtime Data,
and we're gonna expand that table.
So we're gonna create
a few visualizations here,
and they'll populate when
we push data into the dataset.
So the first visualization, we're
gonna grab the table visualization icon,
and we're gonna just add
technology to the table as a field.
And then we'll add, let's
see, we'll add technology.
We'll add, after technology,
let's go ahead and do experience
and location in the table.
And then we're gonna
click on a blank area of the
canvas, and we're gonna
use a map visualization.
In your visualizations pane, the
map visualization looks like a globe.
Go ahead and select that.
And we're gonna use location field
from the Fields pane as the location.
We're gonna use experience as
the legend for the map visualization.
And we're gonna use
technology, actually let's flip that.
Let's use the X to get rid
of experience in the legend.
And let's put technology in the legend.
And then for experience, we're
gonna put a count of experiences,
and that goes in the size
box for the visualization.
So I'm gonna make that
map visualization bigger.
Again, it's not showing any of our data
because we don't have
any data in our data set.
And maybe what I'll do is I'll move the map
to the right side of the table
and then size it from there.
I'm gonna click on a blank
area of the canvas again,
and this time we're gonna
add a stacked column chart.
So I guess that's the second
icon in the visualizations pane.
And we're gonna use,
for the axis, we'll grab
technology and we'll use
experience for the legend.
And again, we're not
seeing anything in these
visualizations 'cause we
don't have any data yet.
We're gonna add one more visualization
and we're gonna use the
card visualization for that.
So make sure you're on a
blank area of your canvas.
Click on the card.
And for the field, we're
gonna use technology.
And notice how when you put it into
the fields box, it says first technology.
We're gonna do the dropdown arrow next to
first technology and choose count distinct.
So how many responses
are there for that technology?
Now we need to save this report.
So you're gonna go up to file
and you're gonna choose save.
And it's gonna want you to name it.
We're gonna just call it
streaming and click save.
(mouse clicking)
So I mentioned earlier, when
you're using streaming data,
you can't use the pen live
experience for dashboards
because it's counterintuitive.
It's real time streaming data,
which means your dashboards will
automatically update as new
data is pushed into the dataset.
So what we need to do to
get these onto a dashboard
is pin them each individually.
If I hover over my empty
technology experience
location table, you'll
see the controls for that.
And the first control is pin visual.
Go ahead and click it.
Notice it shows a little
snapshot of the data.
In our case, we don't have any data yet.
It defaults to a new
dashboard because we are in
a new workspace that
doesn't have any dashboards.
And we're gonna call this
dashboard streaming dashboard.
Notice the pin button
does not say pin live.
It knows that it's streaming.
So it's not gonna offer you that option.
We're gonna go ahead and click pin.
And we don't have to
go to the dashboard yet.
You can just close that pop-up if
you'd like or it'll disappear in a moment.
And then I'm gonna hover
over the map and find its
control buttons, which
are showing up underneath.
I'm gonna grab the pin visual.
And now it's on existing dashboard and it's
the one that we have in this workspace.
So we're gonna just click pin.
I'm gonna hover over the technology
and experience chart and use the pin.
And I'm gonna do the same
for the card visualization
and use the pin.
So now our setup is done in
terms of we have our dashboard.
We've already pinned
our visualizations to it.
We created our dataset,
but it is not populated.
Before we begin the
process of populating our
dataset, let's switch
over to our workspace.
So the streaming dataset workspace, and
let's open up the dashboard that we created.
We wanna make sure everything is
organized on the dashboard accordingly.
So you'll notice when we
were looking at the report,
the card for the count of
technology was over in this area.
We want to move it so that we don't have
to scroll to get to it on the dashboard.
So to move a visualization
on your dashboard,
you wanna look for it's
more options button and you
can click and hold that
and drag it to a new location.
Notice that as you drag it, it might
cause other dashboard tiles to move.
That's because they're taking up the space.
So you'll notice there's a gray box that
pops up and says, hey, that's an empty space.
It might be great for this tile.
So once I've done that,
now what we need to do
is start the process to
populate our dataset.
We're gonna use Power
Automate to create a flow.
Flow is kind of short for workflow.
The flow that we will
create will tell the system
to grab all the responses
from our survey form
that we created and
push them into the dataset.
So we're gonna go access Power Automate.
You can use, if you wanna
stay in Power BI, that's
fine, but you can go
to the Microsoft Waffle
and you'll see all of the apps.
If you wanna open Power
Automate in a new window,
you can use the vertical
ellipsis and say open a new tab.
So go ahead and get
yourself into Power Automate.
It should be the same login
you're using for Power BI.
When you access Power
Automate, you have the option to
start a flow from a template
or you can start from a blank.
We're actually gonna start from a blank.
So on the left side, you
have the menu and on that
menu, you're gonna go
ahead and click on Create.
So this is where it gives you choices.
You can start from blank,
you can start from a template,
and you can start by using a
connector, which is typically another app.
We're going to be using connectors
when we start from a blank one.
So the type of blank flow that we
want is an automated cloud flow.
We have Power BI in the
service, which is online.
We're using a form that we created in
Microsoft Forms, which is also online.
So we're gonna do an automated cloud flow.
And the first thing we
have to do is give it a name.
It says add a name or we'll generate one.
We're gonna name this Streaming Data Flow.
(keyboard clacking)
Now flows respond to triggers.
Something happens that
causes the flow to respond.
The trigger we want is a
Microsoft Forms trigger.
And if it's not showing on
your list when a new response
is submitted, that's the
actual trigger we're gonna use,
you can click in the
search box and type forms,
and it will show all the
different types of form triggers.
So we're gonna go with
when a new response is
submitted, and we're
gonna click on create.
So now for this particular trigger,
you have to tell it which form.
Do the dropdown next to pick a form
and your streaming survey
should show on that list.
So that's the first step, the trigger.
This flow that we're creating will respond
when a new response is
submitted to our streaming survey.
We need to add another step.
So go ahead and click the new step button.
And this is another Microsoft Forms step.
So in the search box, go ahead
and type forms just to narrow the list.
I really can type, promise.
And you'll see that you get some actions.
So when a new response
is submitted is a trigger.
Now, what do you want to happen
when that trigger is activated?
We would like to get the
response details from that form.
So again, it needs the form ID,
and you can do your
dropdown and select streaming
survey, and click in
the response ID field.
You'll get this pop-up on the right
that says add dynamic content from
the apps and connectors used in this flow.
There's only one choice
there and it's response ID.
Go ahead and click on it.
So what it's saying is when a
new response is submitted on the
streaming survey form, get the
response details by response ID.
Each respondent is assigned a response ID.
So each person that takes the
survey is answering three questions.
Their three responses
will have the same ID.
We have to add one more step.
So go ahead and click
your new step button again.
This time, we're using
the Power BI connector.
So in the search box, type Power BI,
and you'll see a list of all
the actions for Power BI.
And the action that we
want is add rows to a dataset.
For that one, we have
to tell it which workspace.
So do your workspace dropdown,
and you're gonna choose your
streaming dataset workspace.
We named the dataset itself the same thing.
So access that dropdown
and make the choice.
And then do the dropdown for the table.
Notice workspace, dataset, and
table all have a red asterisk in front,
which means they are required.
The name of that table,
we saw it when we went
and looked at the
reports, is real-time data.
So once we select
the table, we get three
fields, technology,
experience, and location.
And we have to tell it which
question maps to each field.
So when you click in
technology, on the right
side, you'll have that
dynamic content box,
and it'll show you the questions.
It'll also show you
some other things, but it'll
show you the questions
that we created in our form.
So the first one is which BI technology
are you most interested in learning?
And that's the one we're gonna click on.
For experience, click in the box.
And what is your current experience
level on the technology is the question.
And for location, you're
gonna grab where are you from.
And now we've completed our flow.
A couple of things.
If we had problems with anything we did
in our flow, the flow checker would be red.
Go ahead and click on the flow checker.
You see we have zero
errors and zero warnings,
which is good, we
don't have any problems.
We need to save our flow.
So you can either save it up on the
top or you can save it on the bottom.
And it lets you know when it's saved.
So now you have that green band
that says your flow is ready to go.
We recommend you test it.
What I'd like you to do now
is use the Microsoft Waffle
and open, what I'd like you to do is reopen
forms in a new window or on a new tab.
Go ahead and do that.
So I've arranged my screen.
So I have Microsoft forms on
one side and my dashboard,
my streaming dashboard on the other side.
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
be a respondent for my own survey.
And I'd like you to do the same thing.
What you're gonna do
is click on your survey.
If it's not there, you can
go to all my forms to find it.
So I'm gonna click on the streaming survey.
And in order to respond to it,
I'm gonna click the preview
button up here on the bar.
So now what I'd like you
to do, I would like you to
submit five separate
responses to your own survey.
After you finished the first one,
I'll give you the opportunity
to take the survey again.
Make random answers when
you're going through this process.
And go ahead and get started on doing that.
Now I'm gonna review
the streaming dashboard.
You'll notice that it populated with
my choices from my survey responses.
So the table populated, the map populated,
and you can see the locations on the map.
The count of technology card populated,
but the technology and
experience report did not.
So let's take a look at the report
itself to see what's going on with that.
I'm gonna just return to my
streaming data set workspace.
And I'm gonna select the streaming report.
Once it loads, I'm gonna go
up to more options and edit it.
So it looks like report
view in the desktop.
I'm gonna select that empty visualization.
I can see that it is a
stacked column chart.
And the reason it's not populated
is because we only filled
in the axis and the legend.
We need a value for that chart to populate.
So in your fields pane, expand real-time
data and drag location to the values field.
Because it's a non-numeric
field, it does a count of locations.
So now you'll see that
the chart has populated.
The thing is, at this point, we have to
pin the updated visual to the dashboard.
So go ahead and select the
pin visual push pin above it.
And we're gonna pin it to
our streaming dashboard.
Go ahead and click pin.
And then I'm gonna navigate to
the dashboard from the pop-up.
It's gonna ask me if I wanna save changes
to the report, and I'm gonna choose save.
So now on the dashboard, I have both
the empty one and the populated one.
I'm gonna remove the empty one
by going to its more options
icon and choosing delete tile.
I'm gonna scroll to the right so I can see
the more options for the populated chart.
And I'm gonna click and hold on that and
just drag it over to where the other one was
on the left of the count
of technology card.
So now you've created your push dataset.
Let me go over the process
we went through for this.
We started by creating our form,
and then we came over here
and we created our push dataset.
We created a workspace, a
premium workspace to hold it.
And we also designed our reports.
They were empty until the data got
pushed in when we responded to our survey.
After we designed our reports,
we created our automated flow
so that it's triggered when a
response is submitted on the form
and it grabs the data and
dumps it into our dataset.
One of the things we can do to enhance
our dashboard is to apply a theme to it.
This is very similar to applying a
theme to a report in the service.
And we can access the
themes by going to the edit icon
up at the top of the screen.
And we're gonna select dashboard theme.
The panel opens on the right.
Now there are not as many themes in
the service as they are in the desktop.
So when you do the dropdown next
to light, which is the default theme,
you have dark, colorblind,
friendly, and custom.
I'm gonna select dark and you know,
that could be hard to read
the part of the dashboard
that I see behind it, could
be good for some people.
I'm gonna go back to the dropdown
and select colorblind friendly,
which really looks a lot like
white in here, but apparently
just like in the service, they
have a colorblind friendly theme.
And then I'm gonna go back
one more time and choose custom.
So you can use a background
image for your dashboard.
You can change the color of the background.
So I'm gonna do that by accessing the
color dropdown and I'm gonna choose,
you can make the color
choice that you'd like,
but I'm gonna choose
like this light teal color.
You can have a background
color for the dashboard tiles.
So the things that are on
the dashboard, if you'd like.
Why don't you take a few
moments and go through those
settings and figure out
the way you want it to look.
Once you're done making your choices,
click the save button in
the lower right hand corner.
Another enhancement feature
is to add a video or audio
or even text boxes to your dashboard.
We also use the edit button
to access those features
and you're gonna choose add a tile.
In the add a tile panel, you'll
see that you can add web content.
If you click on web
content and choose next,
you can see that you
can have a title and subtitle
and you would have
to embed the code here.
I'm gonna use the back button.
You can add an image,
a text box or a video here.
I'm gonna go ahead and click on
video and then I'm gonna click next.
So it adds the add video tile box here
and you have to have the video URL
and right now it will only accept
videos that are on YouTube or Vimeo.
Open up a browser window or a
new tab and navigate to YouTube.
At the top of the screen, click in the
search box and type how to use web apps
and at the end type learn
it, all one word, learn it.
Press enter.
So if you scroll down just a little bit,
you'll see Office 365 how to use web apps.
It's by learn it training
and you're gonna click on that
so that the video page comes up.
Now I just stopped the video from playing
because what I wanna do is go all the way
to the top of the screen and see
the address bar where the URL is.
So I'm gonna select, I'm gonna click in
the address bar at the top of the screen
and I'm gonna do control
C to copy that URL.
And I've switched back over to my
supplier quality analysis sample dashboard.
So we can fill in the details in
the add video tile pane on the right.
We're gonna check the box
that says display title and subtitle.
The title is going to be
how to use web apps.
We don't need, well,
we'll put learn it in the
subtitle just so you
can see how that looks.
And in the content
section for the video URL,
you're gonna do control
V as in Victor to paste
and now you're gonna
click the apply button.
You saw the pop-up that said the
content was added to your dashboard.
So everything you add to your dashboard
at this point is gonna go to the bottom.
So I'm scrolling down and you have
the video there on your dashboard.
Now this particular video,
it's a very short video.
That's why I chose it.
It's also from learn it,
another reason why I chose it.
But it has nothing to do
with the supplier quality
analysis data, but just to
give you the information
on how to add videos to
your dashboard to enhance
them is what the
important takeaway is here.
Another feature you can use on your
dashboard is setting a dashboard tile alert.
A tile alert will notify
you when data on a
dashboard changes above
or below limits that you set.
Right now, tile alerts
can only be set on
card, KPI and gauge
visualizations in Power BI.
I'm gonna scroll back to
the top of my dashboard
and I have a total defect quantity card.
If I navigate to it's more
options button and click
it, you'll see that I have
manage alerts there.
Because it's a card visualization,
it allows me this feature.
I'm gonna go ahead and click manage alerts
and the manage alerts box
pops up on the right side.
It lets you know for which card it's for,
because you know sometimes when you're working
fast, you might select the wrong thing.
So it gives you a reminder at the top.
We're gonna click on add alert rule.
It defaults to being active.
You can have alerts set
up and then activate them
that if you don't wanna use
them for a while and then
just reactivate them when
you want to use them again.
We're gonna leave the default title.
It again repeats and in here
it has the name of the field,
the actual name of the field and
the condition defaults to above.
You have a dropdown
where you can choose below
and the threshold, we're gonna put in 35.
On the card right now, we're at 33 million.
So this would be at 35.
You get to select your
notification frequency.
It defaults to every 24 hours.
If you wanna get alerts every
hour, you can change that way.
They will only send if your data changes.
So you will get alerts in
your notification center
in the service and you can opt to
have an email sent to you as well.
I'm gonna uncheck the
send me an email to box.
It's recommending that you
can also use Power Automate
where we set up our flow
to trigger additional actions.
We're gonna do save
and close at the bottom.
So you can only do alerts on cards,
gauges and KPI visuals at this point.
If you opt not to get an email, your
notifications for your alerts can be found
to the left of your login information up
here at the very top right hand corner.
Depending on your
resolution, it might already be
expanded but I'm gonna
click on that settings button
and then I can click on notifications.
So if you have notifications, you can
get them from the notification center.
So when that total defect
quantity gets to 40 or above,
you'll get the notification there.
Again, you can opt to
get it via email as well.
There's an artificial
intelligence visualization
that you can use both in
the desktop and the service
and I'm gonna introduce it to you now.
It is called Q&A for question and answer.
You've noticed since we've
been in the dashboard, in the upper
left hand corner, it says ask
a question about your data.
That's where Q&A resides in the service.
You could also apply it
as a visual on a report.
It functions a little bit
differently in the desktop than
it does in the service but the
end result will be the same.
It's gonna perform analysis on your data.
If you click on that line that says
ask a question about your data,
it'll say it's preparing your Q&A
and when you get in here,
you'll see a series of tiles,
questions that Power BI
determined to ask about your data.
If you have a link on the right
that says show all suggestions, click it
and it will display more
tiles if there are any.
So you can review these tiles
and see what they're saying.
The thing is is there may be
questions that it comes up with
that you look at these and you say,
you know, I should have thought of that.
That is a great question.
You can click on any of
these tiles and see the result.
I'm gonna click on the tile that says
show defect quantity supplies
and total defect quantities.
And when I click on that, it
creates a visualization for me.
So it's showing me the
information I requested.
Now, if I want this information
to be on my dashboard
in the upper right hand
corner, I can click on pen visual
and it's on our existing dashboard.
So we're gonna do pen.
And in the upper left
hand corner of the screen,
you'll see an arrow
and it says exit Q&A.
You can go ahead and click that.
And again, everything
you add to your dashboard
will come up at the bottom
so you can scroll down
and see that new tile that was added.
If you wanna spend a few
moments going back to Q&A,
looking at different tiles and
pinning them or not, feel free to do so.
There's a data analytics feature that's
built into the service called Quick Insights
where Power BI will
analyze all of your data
and offer you a wide
variety of visualizations.
In order to get access to Quick Insights,
we need to go back to our workspace.
So you can use that next to the last button
on the left hand side to get
back to your current workspace.
Quick Insights are performed on datasets.
So we're gonna go to
the more options button
for the supplier quality
analysis sample dataset
and you can click on
Get Quick Insights or
View Insights if you've
accessed this before.
If you're getting Quick Insights,
it'll have a pop-up box
in the upper right hand
corner letting you know
that it's getting them
and when they're ready.
When they're ready, you can go back
to your dataset and click on View Insights
and it tells you these are Quick Insights
for supplier quality analysis sample.
A subset of your data was analyzed
and the following insights were found.
There's a learn more link.
There is help every step along the
way in Power BI which is a good thing.
So it gives you these insights.
Impact has noticeably
more total downtime minutes.
Total downtime minutes
max and total defect reports.
So it gives you visualizations
as well as the written insight.
And just like Q&A, you may come upon
things that you decide, you know what?
I really should have that
visualization on my dashboard.
So the one I'm looking
at, total defect reports by
material type, that might be
good to put on the dashboard.
It has the pin in the
upper right hand corner
and I'm gonna go ahead
and pin it to my dashboard.
You can scroll through these other
insights and if you see anything else
that you wanna add to your
dashboard, go ahead and pin it.
I found another one,
the count of plant by
category that I'm gonna
add to my dashboard.
And then I'm just gonna
go back to my Power BI
video workspace and
access my dashboard again.
And remember, scroll
down and toward the bottom,
you will see the insights that
you just pinned to your dashboard.
I love quick insights in Q&A.
Oftentimes I see things that I hadn't thought
about so they're very helpful features.
There are just a few other
dashboard features I'd like to show you.
One of which is setting
a featured dashboard.
When you set a dashboard,
you can only have one at this time.
As featured, whenever
you go into the service,
it will open with that
dashboard already displayed.
If you have multiple dashboards
that you're working on,
you can set the one that
you're currently working on
as featured and
then set the others as
favorites which gives
you easier access to them.
I'm gonna show you how to set this
dashboard as a featured dashboard.
You're gonna do it by using your more
options button and choose set as featured.
It wants you to confirm
that you do wanna set this
as your featured dashboard,
so I'm gonna confirm it.
And now it lets you
know that it's featured.
So if you go out of the service and
back into it, this dashboard would show.
Now for the others that you work on
frequently, you can make them favorites.
Let's go back to our workspace
and hover over your
retail analysis sample
dashboard and use the
star to add to favorites.
Do the same with your
sample superstore dashboard.
It's easy to navigate
to favorite dashboards
because on your left hand
side in your navigation pane,
you have the favorites icon
and when you click there,
you'll see any dashboards
that you have set as favorites.
If you end up setting
a lot of dashboards as
favorites, instead of scrolling
through what could be
a potentially long list, you can use
the search at the upper left hand corner.
Let's go back to our workspace
and let's go back to our supplier
quality analysis dashboard.
We're not gonna actually
go to the dashboard,
we just wanna be able
to see it on the screen.
To the right of it, you
have your more options.
Go ahead and click that and
choose view usage metrics report.
This is a good report to have.
I mean, you can come in here
and you can see all of the ways
that this dashboard may have
been distributed, the platforms,
how many views per day, unique
viewers per day, shares per day.
It gives you a synopsis
over on the right
side for your total views,
viewers and shares.
It does a ranking in here,
comparing this dashboard
against other dashboards
in your organization.
And it will also show
you the total dashboards
in your organization
and the views by user.
So as people, once you
share and people start
viewing your dashboard, you'll be able
to look at the dashboard usage metrics.
You're able to print your
metrics from the file menu.
You can also export so you
can analyze the metrics in Excel.
You can even pin your
metrics to a dashboard.
The last thing I'm gonna
cover in this module
is how to configure your
dashboard for mobile view.
Nowadays, a lot of people
are accessing information
from their phones or
tablets, so it's important
that they be able to access
your information in that way.
We're gonna go back to our workspace
and we're gonna open up the supplier
quality analysis sample dashboard again.
And by the way, before we do this, if
you go back to more options, you can see
that you can disable this
as the featured dashboard.
If you're pretty much done working on
it and you want another one to open up
when you go into the service,
this is how you disable it.
Again, you're only allowed
to have one featured one.
But to get to the mobile
layout, we're gonna go
to the edit dropdown and we're gonna click
on mobile layout and it changes the view
so it kind of looks
like a cell phone there.
And what you can do is from
here, it has some of the tiles
from the dashboard, it just picks ones that
it think will fit in this mobile layout.
If you wanted to unpin
all of those tiles, you could
from here and if you do
that, then you can reset them.
What we're gonna do is we wanna keep
the top two tiles 'cause those are cards.
Cards are good to put in a mobile layout.
They don't take up too much space.
So for the map, I'm gonna hover
over it and hide the tile so it unpins it.
And for this column
chart, I'm gonna do the
same and you can see
the unpinned tiles here.
Now there's more on here.
We really just wanna keep the cards.
So it pretty much grabbed everything
but you could only view a
certain amount in a mobile layout.
If you wanted to view more, that's fine
but we wanna get rid of
everything that's not a card.
So take some time and do that.
And when you're satisfied
with your mobile view,
it's already set, you can
get back to the other view
by clicking on this mobile layout
button and going back to web layout.
We'll do more work on
workspaces in a later module.
This module was action packed.
We started by creating a
dashboard and pinning visuals to it.
We went in depth with real time dashboards.
So we started by creating a form.
We set up a push dataset,
created some visuals.
We use Power Automate to generate a flow
that would take the data from responses
on the form and push it into the dataset.
And we saw our visualizations populate.
We moved on to enhancing a dashboard
by adding a custom theme and video to it.
We configured a dashboard tile alert.
Again, that's only for gauge
card and KPI visuals at this time.
You got introduced to Q&A
and quick insights for analysis.
And we added some of
the results to the dashboard.
You learned how to set a featured dashboard
and how to unset it because
you're only allowed one.
And you learned that you
can add multiple dashboards
as favorites, so they're
easy to navigate to.
You also learned how to configure
a dashboard for mobile view.
Thanks for watching.
Don't forget we also offer live classes
in Office applications, professional
development and private training.
Visit learnit.com for more details.
Please remember to like and subscribe and
let us know your thoughts in the comments.
Thank you for choosing Learn It.
(gentle music)