I'm sorry Claire, I couldn't hear
you over the announcement.
No problem. So just
checking if my audio is
good and if you can see
my screen, everything
looks good from my
end. I can hear you loud
and clear and yeah
the screen is visible, so
this session's all
yours. Thank you.
Appreciate it. All right, sorry
for the delays here due to
technical issues but now
I'm back. Hey everyone,
thanks for joining. This
is just a quick overview
of what you've already
probably learned regarding
the business analysis and
how the end-to-end might look.
I will just try to paint
a good picture for
you guys on what things are
key in the current day and age.
There is a lot of redundant information about
business analysis out there and the team
wanted to put this
together so you guys are
more on the current page
and are aware of what
technologies and what concepts of business
analysis is being adopted by a lot of these
organizations out there.
So the first thing that
we look at is to define good
business goals and objectives.
Usually when you
think about a product
and you're trying to
develop it, you are focused
on the key results. You
have to define a good
business objective. So
if you define your goals
clear enough and precise
enough, then you should
be able to achieve the
end product right. It's
a very well good job done. So that is why
defining a good business objective and goal
is important and a lot of us follow this
methodology called SMART where the goal needs
to be specific, measurable
in terms of how long
it might take and how
achievable it is and how
realistic it is and what is the timing
that it might take to accomplish that goal.
So the OKR for the abbreviation is the key
results and these define the objectives.
If you think about a newly stand-up project,
it's broken down quarterly based mostly.
So each quarter the team
has certain goals to meet.
So all your sprint goals,
your day-to-day sprint
activities kind of sum up into achieving
that goal that's defined for that quarter.
So these key results are mostly
defined based on the output.
So for example, increase market position
within the autonomous delivery market.
So you as business analysts
are probably coming up
with the key results in collaboration with
your product owners and product managers.
If you are focused on
engineering and development
side of things, you are
also probably focused on
the outcomes where
you can measure things.
For example, how do
you achieve a top position
in a competitive market? How do you define
that? You come up with a gap analysis or
market value ratio and things like that and
come up with the percentages on how much of
an improvement you
want to see in your product
and go from there. So
the five components of a
good objective is defining the activity and
the scope and what benefit it gives to the
organization and what value would the end
customer receive from what you're developing
and what is the business
value. It just sums up
into a wholesome
business goal and objective.
This is just the high
level. This is like an entry
point right to your
projects. When you join an
organization, you are
probably given a lot of
documentation to go
through and you're wondering
where to start, where to
begin and it's important
for you to understand
the objectives of that
particular project in order
to see the bigger vision.
Although you're not making a huge contribution
to defining these objectives maybe,
sometimes you are
playing a crucial role in
probably part of the organization where
they're developing and you don't have
insight into all of this
for the company but
definitely there should
be some documentation
at hand for you to go through
and understand the objectives.
Next up, you are familiar with
waterfall and agile.
The basic difference is
waterfall is very linear.
You go from phase to phase.
It takes however
long it takes for each
phase and user gets the
end product at the very
end of the waterfall
methodology. But incremental
delivery is what the
current organizations are
adopting mostly because
they see that the user
gets value from each
iterative term that you work
on a certain product
development.
So basically just dividing
the whole year or the duration
of the project into iterative sprints
or iterative weeks, however it's useful
for your organization
and coming up with tiny,
small, achieving small
goals at every iteration
and learning from them and learning
and applying all the learnings to the next
sprint so that the user
gets a better value.
There's more improvement
with every sprint
and every product
development life cycle you
go through between
those little iterations.
So there are multiple ways of
following the agile methodology.
There's scrum which is the most
famous, most widely
used I would say.
Some teams also use Kanban
or you've probably also heard
about Azure DevOps
which is just a tool where
the organizations are
tracking end-to-end
visibility into a project. Usually
with scrum they use Jira.
If you are familiar
with Jira you'd know
that they would track
the progress of this work
done and how the velocity
and things like that in Jira.
This is very superficial,
does not give
any insight into what
development work is going on
and the release cycle, the pipelines and
things like that but Azure DevOps is built
to give that end-to-end
picture for the users so
a lot of companies are
adopting that particular
tool at the moment. As
you know scrum follows
sprint iterations. They're
usually two weeks
iterations but Kanban
can also follow the same
life iteration or
duration but it does not
have a defined structure
to a sprint or they
do not have like a
defined structure to tasks
where they estimate tasks
and you know it's more random.
Kanban is adopted
where they don't have to
follow a clear pathway I
would say to the end product.
So understanding the
organization team roles.
Now that you know
the business objective
you try to understand
what team are you part of
and what is the organizational
hierarchy and where
do you stand in that
hierarchy. Are you reporting
to an engineering manager
where you are a support
system for the developers
and you're translating
business requirements,
you are more engaged into
the system requirements
or are you part of the
business group where you are defining the
requirements, you are actually gathering the
requirements and
documenting them and you know
supporting the user
acceptance testing in the end.
So it's important for
you to understand where
your role lies in the
organizational hierarchy
and what your job duties are.
So product management consists
of basically the journey owner
and product manager.
They kind of share their
roles in some organizations.
They sometimes work together.
Sometimes it's just
one person who is a
product manager. They
have the end-to-end idea of
the business, how the business runs,
what expectations are there from the higher
management. They usually
report back to the higher
levels in the organization.
Basically they're
bringing value from
their conversations with
the business expectations
and stakeholders and
multiple stakeholders in a
company probably gather
and talk through the vision
and you know they come
up with the roadmap.
They basically define the
value on how to optimize
customer experience
with the product that
you are developing.
Agile team kind of sits side
by side to product management
where the product
owner is a key player.
Sometimes the business
analyst is also a product owner.
They're expected to at
least understand even if
they don't have any
domain experience or they
don't have a huge insight
into the business, how
the business functions.
They are familiar with
the concepts such as how you connect with
your customer, how you engage with your
customer, how you elicit requirements
and talk to the product manager about
how to prioritize
the backlogs, what is
priority and how you
bring them into the sprint.
Like I already mentioned about the goals.
Every quarter they probably have
three key results they want to see and
they prioritize the backlog based on that.
So if you are interested
in that area, a product
owner is a role that is
truly more focused on the
business side things. Now there's also the
development team of course in Agile team.
They are actually
working on the product.
So all the team backlog
they work through the backlog.
They follow the priority
product owner provides to them.
They build and test and deliver the
products incrementally. Sometimes a business
analyst is part of this development team
and they're working very closely with the
development team where
they're testing the end
product that the developers develop and
documenting the defects, ensuring that the
business value is carried throughout
the development and ensuring that any
issues, any critical
things that come up during
development is reported
back to the product owner
so that they are aware and just
building a gap or a bridge between the
product owner and
the development team.
The scrum master is someone
who is very aware of the Agile
methodologies and they ensure that the team
follows the scrum practices. They keep you,
they make sure that you're not handling or
going through any blockers or impediments.
They check on with you
day to day which is nothing
but the daily stand-ups
right. They just want to
make sure that you're on
track to achieving the sprint goal.
They want to make
sure that you are
understanding what iterative development
means. If you are, you know, you have a
discussion with the
development team or the
business team that is
going away from the topic,
they kind of bring you
back. So they kind of keep
you focused on the sprint
goal. So they're kind of
the gatekeeper for
that. So that's what the
scrum master does.
So this is like a high level
of understanding what your
role is within an organization.
Next, obviously every scrum team
will have a product
goal which is defined by
the product owner
and basically your team,
the scrum team is something that has to be
self-managing and you will have different
members of from
different teams put together
so that it just makes
your life easy right with
you know engaging with them day to day.
For example, if you think about
probably a customer
service team right.
So they are interacting with
the end customers day to day.
How will your development team know
about what their challenges are or what
pain points they're facing
and what things they
would like to see
developed right in the product
and because they are the people interacting
with the end customer. So in that case,
the organizations usually find a
subject matter expert who are nothing but
sneeze right. They bring
them in into the team
so that they can provide
internal insights right to that team.
That's just one team.
If you think about Amazon
website, you can think about the
payments and checkout.
You can think about the
search team as one team.
product detail page
team as one team.
So bringing all of them
together is what scrum does.
You will have sneeze from
every side of the organization
that touches that product
and you are getting
inputs from all of those
people and you have to
consider when you're
coming up with your tasks
and priorities you're engaging
with all of these people.
Sometimes a business analyst also has separate
meetings with these people just to keep
give the time back to
the developers to focus on
the sprint goals right.
So you are in meetings
getting requirements and
you know thinking through
the future just preparing
the backlog for the next
couple of sprints
is your goal right.
So you are making sure all
the information in there is up
to date and current. You are
tracking all the dependencies.
You're ensuring all these sneeze are aware
of what the development is what development
is happening in the
team and things like that.
So very interactive
self-managing and cross-functional.
This is a journey map. I know it's not too
it's probably not very visible right.
Let me try to zoom in.
Okay all right so
that's the journey map.
This is just one template
that a product owner or
a business analyst might
use. This has a list of
things such as if you
think about an end-to-end
flow of you know creating
a patient's you know
interaction with an app
probably they will have
to manage their medical
appointments in an app.
They probably have to
book another appointment.
If they want to reschedule that appointment
they should have that capability to do it
and they should be able
to hold the appointment
time and probably also
follow some app have some
follow-up activities right. So that is the
workflow that is the journey of a patient
when they're using an app. So this template
outlines the outcomes of each of this
activity that they perform
on an app and what
human interactions and
sister interactions there
are and how does the
patient feel about that
particular capability
and if they have any pain
points with you know
each of these steps and how
what is the level of
satisfaction they have how
how do they rate the
application when they
consider each of these
elements in the UI right
and any ideas of improvement
all of these things are captured.
What does this give you?
It gives you an end-to-end
picture of what the actual user
of your map or of your
app is looking into right
how are they interacting.
So from this you can
come up with a lot of
improvements that you can
make to the app how
can you can look at this
and say hey these are
these are n number of pain
points with this workflow
can we make this better
and alleviate some of
these pain points in the
next sprint for the user
if there is so okay the
next step would probably
be oh who else uses this
manage all medical
appointments workflow right so
if there is another user
and they have the same
pain point they want
to make sure that it's
highlighted to the business
and they want to make
sure that there is a
solution out there for them
to you know like elevate
that point and that's a
huge win for the team
right so these are just some
templates that we use to
document the user journey
how they are rating the application
just ensuring that they're following the
what the app is intended
to do sometimes there
is a learning curve if
it's a new person using
an app obviously they
have to go through some
training right so this
map just helps you
distinguish or this these
kind of templates that
just help you understand
those things so this
i think is a very good
exercise if you are
standing a project
from ground up so this is
the initial analysis
that you'll be part of or
probably iterative right
if you want to continue
doing that you send
surveys to the customers
you come up with a own
set of questions where
quantifiable answers
are given right and you
come up with like charts
you know just to show
the customer satisfaction
or appreciation of the
map so there's a lot of
you know work that goes
into the initial standing
up of a product so how
would a story map look
like this is more from the
scrum perspective story
mapping is an exercise is
a similar exercise where
you look at the end-to-end
life cycle of a customer
using a workflow for
example managing an
email and then breaking this
is very high level so there
are users who are your
personas right in a user
story and then there are
goals right these are
very high level then you
break it down into
activities activities are
majorly like high level
activities again tasks
performed when you
think about that workflow
of managing emails they they basically
write read and delete an email these are the
basic functions that you require when
they when you think about managing an email
right and then there
are if you want to further
break down writing an
email there is creating and
sending a basic email they're probably just
opening a text email or deleting the email
right so that is your
minimum viable product that
is the basic skeleton
product that you want to
stand up that is your
priority and everything else
that is an enhancement
will take time and then
that can be deprioritized and that comes
later in your journey right as in the scrum
so this is how you story
map you're just sitting
with a bunch of people
that are involved in the
product development and you basically
use a whiteboard storyboard to come up with
you know any topic that's
given to you and what
you can think of and
then arranging the the
sticky notes or you know
the post-its or whatever
in the right order and
then coming up with a
minimum viable product this is a pretty
interesting exercise that i really enjoy
and i've enjoyed doing
over the course of time
because you kind of
understand the mindset of
the company right what
they're focused on and
where they're going so
it's a good thing to have
the end-to-end understanding of this vision
right next slide i have the scrum artifacts
you are aware of a black backlog there is
a product backlog which is very high level
requirements from the
waterfall methodology if you
think of they are written
in form of user stories
and there is a sprint backlog this is
each product requirement broken down into
development oriented tasks
right and then each increment is
every like the prioritized
task for each sprint
basically so how is
the quality of a product
backlog is it's deep
as in it's detail oriented
it's estimated so you
give the task certain
weightage right of how
long they might take and
all of that will sum
up to if you look at the
right hand bottom corner here you will see
there is um sorry let me zoom in okay oops
okay so a product backlog
probably has a hundred
points worth of user
stories right that that is
probably an epic which
which is huge it's not
broken down it's very
high level it's a business
requirement then further
down the lane you will
go into building like
broking breaking them down
into further um achievable
estimatable um stories
that's a word um and this
these points are usually
two to three sprints worth right so you
can probably finish the whole epic in like
three to four uh sprints which is um if you
think about a sprint as two week duration
um this is how you would
um estimate um so um
usually product owners
follow this methodology
called moscow uh to
prioritize the backlog um which
is must have should
have could have won't have
um you can have in jira
you can have labels uh
attached to each of these
tasks um and you can
prioritize them you can
also have play with it uh
with reporting and things
like that so it's pretty
cool um what's a user
story you are probably aware
of functional user
stories but there are also
technical user stories
these are mostly written
from the systems
perspective in order to achieve
a certain thing um in
a system uh what is a
technical task that
needs to be performed so
when you write user
stories there they follow
the invest model uh
again this acronym is pretty
important where you
understand each of these um
what it stands for right
each of each letter in
that model stands
for um the stories are
independent they're
negotiable what and why is
defined um value they they
you cannot break down a
story point where it
doesn't provide value to this
to the goal like the sprint goal right um
and then it is split into the small enough
stars so that it is
estimable i can get into the
story sizing a little bit
uh but it's the smallest
task you can you should
be able to break it down
uh to a level where it's
it makes sense basically
and that it is testable
right it has an acceptance
criteria um so if you look
at this um the example
of um the story sizing
points here um adding
a single or limited
fields so think of a form
where you're adding a
name for a developer it's
a very minor task right
so they're probably just
enabling some user
field they named it they're
making sure that it
functions well for the user
they're basically just entering a string of
characters in a field that's probably a one
point user story for them
and uh if any validation
needs to be added
external additional validation
such as you know the
user store uh the name field
the first name field should
always have a capital
first letter or it should
only uh have like 10
characters those are
the validation rules that
they build and that is
probably a two point worth
um for user story so
they build up based on um
you know the complexity
of the user story how long
it might take to um you
know complete that user
story so um if like this
is an unsaid rule uh
what i've observed is um
scrum masters kind of go
hey why is the user
story more than 13 points
right so they want the
user story to be less
than 13 points if it's
going over 13 points they
ask you a question if you
can break it down further
into probably a three
pointer or a five pointer
um and um just think
about it um so they question
uh if it can be further
broken down because an
13 pointer will probably
take you two weeks right
to develop it test it uh put it into the qa
bucket test there and go through the stress
testing and things like
that and come to the user
acceptance testing and
then release to the end
customer right so it
takes a long time so they
want to make sure that
any user story that you're
bringing into a sprint
in the two-week iteration
is complete before um
closing the sprint so that
is the goal um so how do
you come up with points uh
is um if if your organization
does not already have
a way of estimating
this usually comes from
going through several
cycles of sprint right
so they start with sprint zero uh they ask
you to estimate if you've estimated a two
two pointer right two for
a one pointer user story
uh in the first sprint you
go through the second
sprint you go through
the third sprint so with
experience you will
understand how long it might
take for you to complete a user story what
dependencies there are uh if you've called
out all the dependencies
in the user story and
everything if the
acceptance criteria is good
there are no questions
right um no lingering
questions and no
follow-ups everything looks
good you get an idea
by the third sprint on what
a one pointer might look
like what a two pointer
might look like so that is what will define
how you give story points to a user story
i hope that's clear you
just go through it and you
will understand uh you
should just have a basic
idea of why you are
giving the story points and
um depending on how
many story points you bring
into a sprint that is
considered the velocity
right like not how much
you bring in but how much
you finish in a sprint
is called velocity so that
is also something that
you have to be aware of
uh so the key differences
between waterfall agile
um you have business
requirements and functional
requirements and waterfall
um and in agile mostly
user stories they follow
a certain format business
requirements are very
high level but functional
requirements are more
systematic system behaviors
systemic behaviors and
they're very detailed um
so it's also important
for a business analyst to
understand the definition
of done um what is the
definition of done for
release right so this is
probably after a couple
of sprints you're releasing
a product to the end
customer and uh you want to
define the done definition
right for that release
which is nothing but
all of the testing is
complete all critical
and high priority defects
are closed there is uh
the exit criteria for that
release has been
complete so you're asking a
question whether it's
ready for the end customer
that is ready to release
to production now um
sprint also has a
similar criteria which is
have all the defects closed did you review
the product with the stakeholders and
gotten their feedback
and then that you have like
release notes each
release will have notes right
so you have to know what
was developed during that
sprint and it's usually
the business analyst job
or someone from the
developer's side if they cannot
i mean if they want to add
more like developmental
notes right development
side of notes they would
add those um what is a
done a definition of done
for story you want to make
sure that the acceptance
criteria is met all the
unit tests and user
acceptance tests are
complete and uh all the
code that has been
developed is sent to the right
pipeline right it's
sitting at the right
environment and it won't
be touched again just
mean uh just making
sure that the goal of the
sprint is achieved and
the user story is basically
um you know like it's
tested and it's all done
um and it's secure um
so these are this is also
important for you to define
hey when you define the
ways of working what
does the definition of done
um some of the scrum
ceremonies you would see
day to day um would
be if you think of a sprint
it usually goes from a
tuesday to wednesday or
a wednesday to tuesday
um usually teams try to
stay away from a monday
start to us to a sprint
or a friday start to a
sprint because it's more
like weekends right and
they do not want any new
uh i new development
starting like on mondays
because you're probably
just coming back from a
weekend or going into a
weekend so they usually
started in the middle of
the spring middle of the
week so think of it as a
wednesday to tuesday in
this case and every day
you'll have a 15 minute
stand up to give updates
on uh it's either in the
morning or in the evening
in the evening you're
telling them what you've
accomplished the whole
day what you're planning
for the next day and
if you have any blockers
right that's all they
discuss sometimes there
are huge discussions on
things that are very
pressing but the scrum uh
agile coaches will want
you to park these items
that um don't take
away all the time uh it's
strictly a 15 minute
stand up you try to stay
within the agenda right
then we have um usually
during the week you
will have to uh plan the
sprint obviously um
every start of the sprint
you will have sprint
planning session for about
two hours where um the
agile coach or the scrum
master is asking you
questions on hey team what
stories do you want
to pull into the sprint
and how much of velocity
do you have how much
uh are you is anybody
going on a vacation uh
and um you know what
all these stories are you
able to finish by the
end of the sprint so these
are the main considerations
that's the first day
of the sprint um sometimes
the sprint planning can
also happen the day
prior like an evening time or
something because they
want to give uh everyone
the time um to work
on the sprint full sprint
right so they either like
put away time uh just
a day prior to the sprint at the end of the
previous sprint or on the day of the sprint
the first day um and during
the week um they might
have depending on how
big the backlog is and how
often the requirements
are changing and how
confident everyone is
to refine the backlog they
will have sessions to
refine the backlog where um
you are probably the
business analyst is probably
the driver of that uh
session um they they get
the priority from product
managers and owners
and they look at all
the sprint tasks that are
sitting in the backlog
and they refine them they
review them with the team
they get inputs as much
as they can they identify
risks and assumptions
and dependencies
and make sure all of it is
documented right that's
the refinement session
um if the backlog uh if
the developers need a
session for development
side of things they also
can have an hour session
right during the week um
in the end of the sprint
usually there's a sprint
review if there are
deliverable products by the
end of the sprint they
review the development
done so far with the
stakeholders just to get
their alignment and you
know thumbs up on the
things developed they
want to make sure everything
is developed according
to the requirements
sometimes um things
are lost in translation they
want to make sure that
the definition of done is
achieved right um then
um there's also time for
retro where retrospective
is more um looking back
into things uh on how
the sprint went and if there
were any challenges for
the team if there was any
learnings if anyone had
done a very good job at
you know like working
with the team and bringing
it together you know
that is a time when they
reflect on the past
sprint and make sure that
any learnings outcomes
anything they can improve
the team's functioning
um that is incorporated
into the next thing so
it's the scrum master's job
to pay attention to that
and make sure that the
team team's problems
are heard and yeah ensure
everything is good so
that's the last day of the
sprint uh this is basically
the documentation
i've uh i've put together
for you just to give
you an end-to-end picture
um if this information
is very redundant you
might have some practical
questions to ask me
at this point um if i've
clarified your answers
like i'd like to know
um if you if you have
any feedback i'd like
to know um so that's
the end of this present
over to you guys if you have
any questions for me or feedback
or if you want to see anything else
or know anything else let me know
so i got one question you mentioned
about this akeel uh you mentioned about
product honor right
while explaining this print
and um and the yeah the
scrum cycle i don't know
which slide it was uh yeah so you were just
bringing that particular uh designation to
explain the scrum or
there's certain uh you know
protocols need to be
followed based on designation
or scrum is equal for
every every designation
no matter if it is c-level
or developer whatever
you got my question um
like any special attention
need to be taken by
product owner that's what i'm
trying to say while he's using the scrum in
a in a layman language that's my question
oh any rules per se yeah let's say
yeah let's say um let's say a person um is
is holding a position
called product owner correct
yeah and then he got
his user story uh in the
system so does he have
he or she have to really
focus on certain things
or the all the rule for
scrum is equal for
everyone like ajal is for
everyone because i'm i'm
coming from background
let's say if i need to
evaluate someone is working
with me as a product
owner what exactly i need to
check while you know over
weaving his scrum board
so product owners they
usually uh own the product
backlog right so they
know what user stories
there are they have to
be able to give you um
the details and you
know the insight into what
a user story should
contain what the acceptance
criteria is so they
basically define the product
for you they understand
the vision from the higher
level management and
they're supposed to translate
that to you guys if you
are the developer ensure
that all of the
vision is put into the
requirements which is
nothing but the user stories
so they are very actively
participating in the
product refinement sessions
which are the backlog
grooming sessions
because that is where their
input is required and
also during sprint planning
where they prioritize
the user stories that
are brought into the
sprint so and during this
sprint also if there
are any questions for
developers you know
they during the stand-up
they attend the stand-up
so the developers are
talking about the things
that they're developing
for that day and if they
have questions they
follow up with the product
owner to give clarity
so that is their role
basically and at the end of
this sprint there when
you are as a developer if
you're reviewing a
certain capability right so
the product owners
are just making sure that
you know the requirement and
the vision has been achieved
okay yeah they are part of scrum because
they ask the important people right to
translate the business
requirements for you guys so yeah
i hope i answered your question do
you have a follow-up question no that's
that's good thank you so much
appreciate it of course anybody else
okay
okay i see this widget
has a comment but it's not
related to the ppt so i'd
let shweta or chris take
it up so guys i think that's the end of the
session thanks for joining i think shweta
and chris will guide you
through the next steps
you will be receiving an
assessment from me or
from the team and i
would expect you to return
it in a day or two so i
can review your learnings
and insights and i'm
looking forward for you to
incorporating the
learnings from this session
and all your sessions previously into that
assessment it's kind of a holistic approach
to understand where
you are stand and how you
understand it also it's
also to help you basically
to understand you know
the basic concepts and
how to apply it in a
day-to-day scenarios right
when you're working as a business analyst
so just ponder upon the questions and
try to answer based on the level of
understanding sorry what was that
okay yeah just you know
i know a lot of you want
to use chat gpt but if
you do that then you won't
learn anything from you
know it's really hard to
understand what the
questions actually are meant
to do for you so i
want you to take the full
benefit of it and there's
no harsh assessment or
you know ruling on any
of that any of your answers
if there is something that
seems out of whack for
me then i will make sure
to respond and you know
guide you in the right
direction just take full
advantage of these
sessions so that you're
learning and you know
just bettering yourself
at what you do for the
future you're welcome to
ask me any questions
and respond to that thread
email thread you you'll
have with me so thank you
all shweta over to you
if you have anything for
the team um chris are
you on oh i don't see any
of these guys on so i'll
let you adjourn and then
i'll have the team reach
out to you regarding
this estimate okay have
a great evening talk soon
thank you so much thank you thank you
[BLANK_AUDIO]